(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-19T22:57:42.271886",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
せーの
One, two...
でも そんなんじゃダメ
But that's simply not enough.
もう そんなんじゃほら
Look, that's just not going to do.
心は進化するよ
My heart is evolving,
もっと もっと
more and more!
恋愛サーキュレーション
[Song: Renai Circulation]
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If our relationship would fade if put into words,
言葉を消せばいいやって
then we should just get rid of words, I thought.
思ってた 恐れてた
That's what I believed, and what I feared.
だけど あれ？ なんか違うかも
But wait, huh? Maybe that's not right.
千里の道も一歩から
Even a journey of a thousand miles begins with a step.
石のように固いそんな意志で
With a resolve as solid as a stone,
塵も積もれば大和撫子？
even dust, when piled up, can become an ideal girl?
「し」抜きで いや「死ぬ気」で！
Without the letter "shi"... no, with all my life!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy and light, floating and soft,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ
just you calling my name...
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
...makes me float right up into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating and soft, fluffy and light,
あなたが笑っている
just seeing you smile...
それだけで笑顔になる
...brings a smile straight to my face.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's just a prank of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが 幸せなの
...I'm so happy that we were able to meet.
でも そんなんじゃダメ
But that's simply not enough.
もう そんなんじゃほら
Look, that's just not going to do.
心は進化するよ
My heart is evolving,
もっと もっと
more and more!
そう そんなんじゃいや
Yeah, I won't have it that way.
ねぇ そんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's still not quite it.
私のこと見ててね
So keep your eyes on me,
ずっと ずっと
forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど
Compared to how big you are inside of me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
my existence inside of you is...
まだまだ 大きくないことも
...still not very big, I know,
分かってるけれど
but even so...
今この同じ瞬間
At this very same moment right now,
共有してる実感
I can feel us sharing this time.
塵も積もれば大和撫子
Accumulating bits by bits to be your ideal girl,
略して、ちりつも大和撫子！
in short, Chiri-Tsumo Yamato Nadeshiko!
くらくらり くらくらる
My head spins round and round...
あなたを見かけたら それだけで 眩しすぎて
Just by catching a glimpse of you, it's too dazzling.
くらくらる くらくらり
My head spins round and round...
あなたを想っている それだけで とけてしまう
Just by thinking of you, I start to melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's a prank of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが
being able to meet you...
幸せなの
...makes me so happy.
「１、２、３、４」
“One, two, three, four”
「サーキュレーション、１、２、３、４」
“Circulation, one, two, three, four”
「１、２、３、４」
“One, two, three, four”
「サーキュレーション、１、２、３、４」
“Circulation, one, two, three, four”
「１、２、３、４」
“One, two, three, four”
「サーキュレーション、１、２、３、４」
“Circulation, one, two, three, four”
「１、２、３、４」
“One, two, three, four”
「サーキュレーション、１、２、３、４」
“Circulation, one, two, three, four”
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Floating softly, floating gently...
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで 宙へ浮かぶ
Just by you calling my name, I float up into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating gently, floating softly...
あなたが笑っている それだけで 笑顔になる
Just by you smiling, it puts a smile on my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's a prank of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが
being able to meet you...
幸せなの
...makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that won't do.
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
See, that's not enough anymore.
心は進化するよ もっと もっと
My heart will evolve more and more.
そう そんなんじゃ いや
Yes, I don't want it to stay that way.
ねぇ そんなんじゃ まだ
Hey, that's still not enough.
私のこと見ててね ずっと ずっと
Keep looking at me forever and ever.
逆光のフリューゲル
[Song: Flügel of Backlight]
「聞こえますか…？」激情奏でるムジーク
“Can you hear it...?” Musik playing with passion
天に解き放て
Release it to the heavens
「聴こえますか…？」イノチ始まる脈動
“Can you hear it...?” The pulse where life begins
愛を突き上げて
Raise your love high
遥か
Faraway,
彼方
beyond,
星が音楽となった…彼の日
the day the stars became music...
風が
The wind
髪を
sweeps
さらう瞬間
my hair away...
君と僕はコドウを歌にした
You and I turned our heartbeats into a song.
そして
And so,
夢は
dreams will
開くよ
open up
見た事ない世界の果てへ
to the end of a world we've never seen before!
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない
Even God doesn't know!
光で歴史を創ろう
We will create history with our light!
逆光のシャワー
Shower of backlight,
未来照らす
illuminating the future
一緒に飛ばないか
Won't you fly with me?
Just feeling
涙で濡れた羽
Our wings drenched in tears...
重くて羽撃けない日は
On days they are too heavy to flap...
WISH
その右手に添えよう
I will place my hand on your right hand
僕のチカラも…
along with my power too!
二人でなら
If we're together,
翼になれる
we can become wings!
Singing heart
いつの日か解る時が来るから
Because the day we understand will surely come
ずっと…忘れない
I will never... forget it.
その時には心のあるがままに
At that time, let your heart lead you,
笑顔で…
with a smile...
笑顔...忘れない
Your smile... I will never forget.
きっと 僕と 君は
Surely, you and I...
一羽の鳥のように
...like a single bird...
遠い 過去を 捨てて 手と手 繋ぎ
...will cast aside the distant past, holding hands,
大空を 強く 翔けていたんだ
and fly powerfully through the vast sky.
そして 生きる 今を
And so, living in the present,
見た事ない 明日の 先へ
towards an unseen future ahead.
Yes, just believe
1000年後の今日も
Even a thousand years from today,
生まれ変わって歌いたい
I want to be reborn and sing with you.
暖かいよ この温もり
It's so warm, this gentle warmth.
絶対離さない Just feeling
I will never let go, I'm just feeling.
運命なんてない
There is no such thing as fate.
物語は自分にある Just
Our story lies within ourselves. Just...
逃げ出したくなったら
If you ever feel like running away,
宇宙を（空を）見上げよう
let's look up at the universe/sky.
勇気こそが 輝くんだよ
Our courage itself is what shines.
Singing star
遥か 星が
A distant star...
音楽となったあの日
...turned into music on that day.
多分 僕は 君と出会い<
Perhaps, my meeting with you...
神話の一つのように 紡いだ
...was spun like a tale from myth.
何も 怖くないよ
There is nothing to fear.
見た事ない 世界の 果てへ
To the ends of a world we've never seen.
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない
Even unknown to God,
光で歴史を創ろう
let us create history with our light.
逆光のシャワー
A shower of backlighting
未来照らす
illuminates the future.
一緒に飛ばないか Just feeling
Won't you fly with me? Just feeling.
涙で濡れた羽根
Our wings, wet with tears,
重くて羽撃けない日は
are too heavy to flap on some days...
旋律は溶け合って
But our melodies blend together,
シンフォニーへと
turning into a symphony.
二人でなら翼になれる
Together, we can become wings.
Singing heart
もっと高く
Higher still...
太陽よりも高く
...even higher than the sun.
Unhappy
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man,
Unlucky?
いかれた現世
in this crazy world.
Be happy? 地獄を抜け出して
Be happy? Escape from hell,
生きているんだし
after all, you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past you turned away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future.
カウンセリング やれやれ
Let's get counseling, dear me,
古今東西 ピースピース
peace-peace all over the world!
Unhappy
Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead!
ねえねえねえ 何だかどうしても
Hey, hey, hey, for some reason,
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm constantly fighting.
触れられない 触れたくもない
Untouchable, don't want to touch,
過去の自分
my past self.
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
A showdown with a transparent ghost long dead.
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
In the depths of innocent, painful memories.
残念
Unfortunate,
もう居ないのに
you're not even here anymore.
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分
The one being seen through is my current self.
ナンセンス
Nonsense,
消えないレッテル
this label won't fade.
胃を這うコンプレックス
A complex crawling through my stomach,
取り憑かれているみたい 巻き付いたまま
I seem possessed, wrapped up in it tightly.
未だ 離れない
It still won't let go.
愛しい日の自分
My self from those beloved days...
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
this chain of you and yourself.
生きていることは 変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Do not settle for unhappiness and be satisfied.
幸せになろうと しないなんて 卑怯だ
Not trying to be happy is just cowardly.
この世 この世は奇奇怪怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Who knows what demon or serpent will appear next.
出会って遭って やっと始まる物語
Meeting, clashing, and finally the story begins.
人か化物か 戯言はピースピース
Human or monster? This nonsense is peace-peace!
Past
& Future
can't change the Past
Past
& Future
run for the Future
トントン
Knock, knock.
何だかどうしても
For some reason,
未来に何某の
towards the future, there is some kind of...
希望もない 期待出来ない ような気がして
feeling of no hope or expectation.
もう随分生きている 既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with the templates and deja vu of a long life.
素敵な出来事の 気配もない
There isn't even a hint of something wonderful.
残念
Regrettable.
積んだ経験の因果
The karma of accumulated experiences,
形骸化された神話 退屈な進化
a myth reduced to a mere shell, a tedious evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Basically, I just want some excitement.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I've got tired of it, got used to it.
なんて
Just kidding.
整っていくガイダンス
The guidance coming together,
増えるコンプライアンス
and the increasing compliance.
蓋を閉じてくみたい
It's like closing a lid,
吸い尽くして
sucking it all dry...
あれも これも どれも 同じ味がする
This, that, and everything else all taste the same.
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
I'm not dead—the chain of you and your kind.
何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future exist right here in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your existence with utmost honesty!
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
UNDEAD 死んじゃいない
UNDEAD! I'm not dead!
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking directly to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness; remain human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just enduring the pain you've grown used to,
死んでるも同然 屍同然のUNDEAD
you might as well be dead—a corpse-like UNDEAD.
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
UNHAPPY? O struggling child of man.
UNLUCKY? 成らざる者も保存
UNLUCKY? Even you, the incomplete ones.
BE HAPPY! 怠わず目指せよ
BE HAPPY! Aim without slacking!
生きているなら
If you are alive...
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるも
Whether you drown in misery or find happiness,
そう全部全部お前だ
yes, it's entirely up to you!
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
East and West, one and all, all creation—peace, peace!
Past & Future, can't change the Past
Past & Future, run for the Future
人並外れたこの愛しさ
This extraordinary, beloved thing—
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
survive through this story filled only with monsters!
Stop, listen, rewind, come a little closer
Listen to the silence beating hard, wherever you go
Fast forward in time, time's moving in deeper
All deeper and deeper into you, there is no way out
It must have been the time when I lost my way
Through the chaos of time, it was stormy
Spinning out of it all, you left me in a life of confusion
Take a time to remember when I met you
See the truth beneath all the lies and hate
Nothing wrong being scared, we're all the same tomorrow
Hear what I'm saying
Rewind your vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back and today
Just explore
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
Stop my tears, rewind
Overlapping blue shadows
Touching in the darkness far away, wishing it was real
Stay with me tonight
I don't want this sadness
Sadness overflowing in my mind
I wanna hold on
Hear what I'm saying
Rewind your vision
I want your heartbeat
I want you wanting me
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
I can't remember days without you
Take my hand
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
with...
lonely night...
I want...
other world...
to the other...
nothing more...
oh yeah...
Rewind our vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back into today
Just explore
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
let me know why
Between us love
いつもどおりのある日の事 君は突然立ち上がり言った
On a day like any other day,
you suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜 星を見に行こう」
"Tonight, let's go see the stars."
「たまには良いこと言うんだね」なんてみんなして言って笑った
"You say good things once in a while,"
we all said and laughed.
明かりもない道を
On a street with no lights...
バカみたいに はしゃいで歩いた
...we walked, frolicking like idiots...
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に 押しつぶされないように
...so we wouldn't be crushed
by the loneliness and anxiety we carried.
真っ暗な世界から見上げた
Looking up from a pitch-black world...
夜空は星が降るようで
...the night sky looked like stars were falling.
いつからだろう 君の事を
Since when did I start...
追いかける私がいた
...chasing after you?
どうかお願い 驚かないで
Please, I beg you, don't be surprised...
聞いてよ 私のこの想いを
...and listen to these feelings of mine.
「あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ」
"That's Deneb, Altair, and Vega."
君は指さす夏の大三角
You point to the Summer Triangle.
覚えて空を見る
I'll remember that as I look at the sky.
やっと見つけた織姫様
I finally found Vega...
だけどどこだろう彦星様
...but where is Altair?
これじゃひとりぼっち
At this rate, she'll be all alone.
楽しげなひとつ隣の君
Next to me, you seemed so happy.
私は何も言えなくて
I couldn't say a word.
本当はね ずっと君の事を
In truth, for a long time...
どこかでわかっていた
...I had known deep down...
見つかったって 届きはしない
...that even if found,
my feelings wouldn't reach you.
だめだよ 泣かないで
"It's no use, don't cry."
そう言い聞かせた
That's what I told myself.
強がる私は臆病で
Putting on a tough front, I was just a coward...
興味がないようなふりをしていた
...pretending I wasn't interested.
だけど
And yet...
胸を刺す痛みは増していく
...the pain piercing my chest only grew.
そうか 好きになるってこういう事なんだね
Ah, I see. To fall in love is to feel like this.
どうしたい？言ってごらん
What do you want to do? Tell me.
心の中 声がする
A voice echoes within my heart.
君の隣がいい
I want to be by your side.
真実は残酷だ
The truth is cruel.
言えなかった
I couldn't say it.
二度と戻れない あの夏の日
That summer day we can never return to.
きらめく星
The glittering stars...
今でも思い出せるよ
I can still remember them even now.
笑った顔も
Your smiling face...
怒った顔も
...and your angry face too.
大好きでした
I loved you so much.
おかしいよね
It's funny, isn't it?
わかってたのに
Even though I knew...
君の知らない
...it's a secret of mine...
私だけの秘密
...that you know nothing about.
夜を越えて
Passing through the night...
遠い思い出の
...into distant memories.
君が指をさす
You point your finger...
無邪気な声で
...with an innocent voice.
I know this will not remain forever
However it's beautiful
Your eyes, hands and your warm smile
They're my treasure
It's hard to forget
I wish there was a solution
Don't spend your time in confusion
I'll turn back now and spread
My broken wings
still strong enough to cross the ocean with
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Higher and higher in the light
still strong enough to cross the ocean with
My broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Across the sky, just keep on
flying
計測のできない痛みと
With an immeasurable pain...
計測のできない時間の流れが
...and the flow of immeasurable time...
すべてを埋めてしまおうとしても
...even if they try to bury everything,
それでも私には感じられる
I can still feel it.
空から落ちてくるのは
What falls from the sky...
雨ではなくて...
...is not the rain...
Did I ever chain you down to my heart
Cause I was afraid of you?
Because I was afraid of you?
No, I couldn't hold any longer
Love is not a toy
Let go of me now
The time we spent is perpetual
Our future is not real
so I'll leap into the air
My broken wings
Still strong enough
to cross the ocean with my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind?
Higher and higher in the light
Still strong enough
to cross the ocean with my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind?
Across the sky, just keep on...
...flying
空から落ちてくるのは...
What falls from the sky...
あれは雨ではなくて...
...is not rain...
認めていた 臆病な過去
I had accepted my cowardly past
わからないままに 怖がっていた
And remained afraid without understanding
後ろの自分が 現実を今に
My past self casts its reality
映す
...onto the present
いつもの空は 赤く染まっていく
The usual sky is stained in red
ここはきっと 果てない心
Fill up my heart here...
満たして
...in this boundless place
夢で高く飛んだ
In my dreams, I flew high
体はどんな 不安まとっても 振り払っていく
No matter what anxiety wraps around me, I will shake it off
眠る小さな思い
The small, sleeping feelings...
広がりだして 気付く弱い私 君がいれば
...begin to spread, and I realize my weakness, but if you are here...
暗い世界
...in this dark world...
強く居れた
...I could stay strong
長い夢見る心は そう永遠で
This heart, dreaming a long dream, is indeed eternal
I wanna always be with you
I'll give you everything I have
探していた 導く光
I was searching for a guiding light
触れれば すべてを捨てていく
If I touch it, I will cast everything aside
思い出して かけがえのない大切な今を
Remembering this irreplaceable, precious present...
くれる
...that you give me
目を落とし 世界を知った
I looked down and learned of the world
それはいつも 温かいのに
Even though it is always warm...
痛くて
...it hurts
繋がった 確かな願いが
Our connected, certain wishes...
重なり合って見えた 迷いは動き始めた
...overlap, and the doubts that I saw began to move
君を守りたくて 手を握り続けた
Wanting to protect you, I kept holding your hand
深い眠りの中 ただ漂った
Inside a deep sleep, I simply drifted
変わらない 約束だった
It was an unchanging promise
二人信じた絆は そう鮮明に
The bond we both believed in is indeed vivid
声が届くまで
Until my voice reaches you...
名前を呼んで
...call my name
出会えた奇跡 感じたいもっと
I want to feel the miracle of our meeting even more
夢で高く飛んだ
In my dreams, I flew high
体はどんな 不安まとっても 振り払っていく
No matter what anxiety wraps around me, I will shake it off
眠る小さな思い
The small, sleeping feelings...
広がりだして 気付く弱い私 君がいれば
...begin to spread, and I realize my weakness, but if you are here...
暗い世界 強く居れた
I could stay strong in this dark world
長い夢見る心は そう永遠で
This heart, dreaming a long dream, is indeed eternal
I wanna always be with you
I wanna hold you tight right now
I swear I will wipe your tears
I'll give you everything I have
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole wide world
そういう扱い 心得てよね
Treat me like one, okay?
よね
Okay?
その一 いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Number one: Notice when I get a different haircut
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね？
Number two: Make sure to look all the way down to my shoes, got it?
その三 私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Answer every word of mine with three sentences
わかったら右手がお留守なのを なんとかして！
If you understand, do something about my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm trying to be selfish or anything
キミに心から思って欲しいの
I just want you to think from the bottom of your heart...
「かわいい」って
...that I'm cute
かわいいって
That I'm cute
かわいい
Cute
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole wide world
気がついて ねえねえ 待たせるなんて論外よ
Notice me, hey, keeping me waiting is out of the question
私を誰だと思っているの？ もう、なんだか
Who do you think I am? Honestly, I feel like...
甘いものが食べたい！
...eating something sweet!
今すぐによ
Right this instant!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ 文句は許しませんの
Flaws? You mean "cute", right? I won't accept any complaints!
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いて？ ちょっと…
Hey, listen to me properly, will you? Hey...
あ、それとね 白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ？迎えに来て
Oh, and a white horse is a must, right? Come pick me up
わかったらかしずいて 手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, bow down, take my hand, and call me "Princess"
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm trying to be selfish or anything
でもね 少し位叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit
いいのよ
It's okay
世界で私だけのおうじさま
My one and only prince in the whole wide world
気がついて ほらほら おててが空いてます
Notice me, look, my hand is empty
無口で無愛想な王子様
My quiet and unsociable prince
もう、どうして！ 気がついてよ早く
Oh, seriously, why?! Hurry up and notice!
絶対
You definitely...
キミはわかってない わかってないわ
...just don't get it, you don't get it at all!
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake
こだわりたまごの とろけるプリン
Melting pudding made with select eggs
みんな みんな 我慢します
I'll hold back on all, all of them
わがままな子だと思わないで
So don't think I'm a selfish girl
私だってやればできるもん あとで後悔するわよ
I can do it if I try! You'll regret it later, you know
当然です！だって私は
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
...the number one princess in the whole wide world
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Make sure to watch me properly, or I'll go somewhere else!
不意に抱きしめられた 急に そんな え？
You suddenly hugged me... out of nowhere, wait, what?
「轢かれる、危ないよ」そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
"You'll get run over, it's dangerous," you said, turning away
…こっちのが危ないわよ
...you are the one who's dangerous to my heart
はい！ということで、皆さん！
Okay! And with that, everyone!
獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026「STRAY and STAY」にお越しくださりありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to Shishiro Botan Birthday Festival 2026 "STRAY and STAY"!
ということで、ライオン、獅白ぼたんでーす。
And so, I'm the lion, Shishiro Botan!
配信のハッシュタグ、改めて右上、右上？
Once again, the hashtag for the stream is on the top right... top right?
どっちだ？（笑）どっちか！よろしくお願いします。こっちです！
Which side is it? (laughs) Whichever! Please use it. This way!
獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026、たくさん呟いてください。私もチェックしますんでよろしくお願いします！
Please tweet a lot with #ShishiroBotanBirthdayFestival2026. I'll be checking them, so thank you!
ということで、さっそくなんですけど、
So, without further ado,
次のパートの、ま、次の、次かな？ちょっと色々あるんですけど。
let's call on the guests for the next part... or is it the part after next?
ま、次のパートのゲストをお呼びして、一緒にちょっとMCやっていきたいと思います。
Well, there's a lot going on, but let's welcome the guests for the next part and do an MC segment together.
ということで、来いよ、いつものメンバーたちよ！
So, come on out, the usual crew!
来たぜ、いつもの。
Here they are, the usual crew.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you for having us!
いつものメンバーたちということで。
Since the usual crew is here,
じゃあちょっと改めて自己紹介してもらおうかな。はい、ねねちから。
let's have everyone introduce themselves. Nene-chi, go ahead.
はい！ねぽらぼの「ね」、桃鈴ねねです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! The \"Ne\" of NePoLaBo, Momosuzu Nene here! Nice to meet you!
はい、次！ねぽらぼの「ぽ」、尾丸ポルカです。よろしくお願いします。
Okay, next! The \"Po\" of NePoLaBo, Omaru Polka here. Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ら」、ホロライブ5期生、顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです。よろしくお願いします。
Yes! The \"La\" of NePoLaBo, Hololive Gen 5, \"My Liver is My Face,\" Yukihana Lamy here! Nice to meet you!
ということで、お馴染みのメンツ揃いました。
And with that, the usual lineup is assembled.
ししろん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shishiron, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます。で、生誕祭、始まっちゃいましたけど、これ、どう、どうですか？
Thank you. Now that the birthday festival has started, how does it feel?
どうですか？どうですか？
How does it feel?
お馴染みの顔を見ると安心するね。
Seeing familiar faces really puts me at ease.
いやもう、来年もよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to working with you next year too.
よいお年を、みたいな。
Like, \"Have a happy New Year.\"
ステージめっちゃかっこよくない？
Isn't this stage super cool?
ステージね、かっこいいよね。かっこいいでしょ。
Yeah, the stage is really cool. Cool, right?
好きだよ、こういうの。
I love this kind of style.
好きだよね。やっぱ好きなの結構、あの、めっちゃディグるほうだからさ。こういうの、めっちゃ使っちゃうよね。
I know. Since I'm the type who really digs into what I like, I end up using a lot of it.
要素いっぱいだね。そうそうそう、近未来的。
There are so many elements. Yes, it's very futuristic.
そうなんですよ。
That's how it is.
ちなみにコンセプトとかあるんですか？
By the way, is there a concept behind it?
今回結構、アニメの曲とかもたくさん歌わせてもらってたので、
This time, I sang quite a lot of anime songs,
プラス、なんか私の好きな、その、EDMというか、サイバー感が好きなんで、
plus, I really like EDM and that cyber feel,
ちょっと合体した感じかな？ドパってる、ドパってる感じ。
so it's a bit of a fusion. It's got that dopamine-pumping feel.
ドパってる？
Dopamine-pumping?
うん、ちょっとドパってる感じ。
Yeah, a bit of a dopamine-pumping feel.
はい、ということでね。ここまでの、まあいろいろ振り返ってもみようかなと思ったんですけど、
Yes, and so, I thought about looking back on what we've done so far,
どうしようかな？
but what should we do?
なんか、私、今日、一曲目にさ、「恋愛サーキュレーション」を歌ったんですよ。
Actually, for the first song today, I sang \"Renai Circulation.\"
おー！可愛かったよ。
Oh! You were so cute!
可愛かったか？ちょっと久しぶりに、なんか可愛いのをごちそうしちゃったなと思って。
Was I cute? It's been a while, so I thought I'd treat everyone to something cute.
照れてる、照れてる。ブリッコ。可愛いよ。
You're blushing! Showing off! You are cute!
四歳、四歳が出てたよ。出てた？
Your four-year-old self was showing. Was it?
今回で、何歳になった？
How old did you turn this time?
今回、でも四歳から、次の「フリューゲル」そらちゃんと歌った時に、もう仕様、二十歳くらいになった。
This time, I went from four to about twenty when I sang \"Flügel\" with Sora-chan.
飛んだ、かっこいい。そう、飛んだから。
You skipped a lot! Cool! Yeah, because it skipped.
色々ちょっと、MCがてら紹介したいことがあって。
There are a few things I'd like to introduce during this MC segment.
ちょっとお手伝いしていただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
I'd be glad if you could help me out.
はい、何でしょう？じゃあちょっと告知、はい、告知させていただきたいと思います。
Sure, what is it? Well, I have some announcements to make.
まずは、獅白ぼたん生誕、えー生誕記念2026のグッズの販売告知となります。
First up, we have the sales announcement for Shishiro Botan Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise!
こちら、じゃーん。
Here it is, ta-da!
はい、イラストはママ、トマリ先生に描いていただきました。ありがとうございます。
Yes, the illustration was drawn by my mama, Tomari-sensei. Thank you so much.
イラストのテーマはね、ちょっとゴシック系の獅白ぼたんに仕上げていただきました。
The theme of the illustration is a Gothic-style Shishiro Botan.
似合ってる、似合ってる！いいでしょ？
It really suits you! Great, right?
じゃあ詳細ちょっと見ていきましょう、こちら。はい、ドドン。はい、ステッカー。
Let's take a look at the details. Here they are, ta-da! First, the sticker.
これはキービジュアルのイラストを使用した大きめサイズのステッカーです。
This is a large-sized sticker featuring the key visual illustration.
貼って剥がせるタイプになってるんで、何回でも、はい、使えるかなと思ってます。キラキラホログラム仕様です。
It's a peel-and-stick type, so you can reuse it multiple times. It has a sparkly hologram finish.
おー！じゃあ続いてはこちら、ドン。
Oh! Next up is this, ta-da!
SSRBのエコバッグです。
The SSRB eco-bag!
ちょっとしたお買い物にね、気軽に持ち歩けるエコバッグになってます。
It's an eco-bag you can easily carry around for quick shopping trips.
SSRB型のポーチも付属してるので、その中に収納していただければね、持ち運びも簡単になるかなと、はい、思います。
It also comes with an SSRB-shaped pouch, so storing it inside makes it easy to carry around.
はい、続いてはこちら、ドドン。
Next is this, ta-da!
コンテナボックス。
The container box.
リバイバル？リバイバルだけど、デザインは変わんで。
A revival? It is a revival, but the design has changed.
はい、SSRBデザインのコンテナボックスになってて、折りたためる、はい、仕様になってます。
Yes, it's an SSRB-designed container box, and it's foldable.
これめちゃめちゃ人気だったもんね。
This one was super popular before.
そうそう。で、やっぱね、みんなグッズ増えてきてると思うんで、収納して、そうそう、収納していただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
Since everyone's merch collection is growing, I hope you can use this to store them.
はい、続いてはこちら。
Next is this one.
SSRBのティッシュカバーです。
The SSRB tissue cover!
手触り感のね、SSRBモチーフのティッシュカバーになってるんで、いつでも手元に置いてね、
It's a soft, SSRB-themed tissue cover, so keep it close by
なんか涙拭いたりしてくれよな。
to wipe your tears.
ふわふわ。ふわふわ仕様。ふわふわ仕様。
Fluffy! A fluffy version.
そして、フルセット購入特典あります。こちら。
And there is a full set purchase bonus! Here it is.
直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りのポストカードです。イラスト、もうママのイラストが最高なんで。
A postcard with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped printed message. The illustration by Mama is just the best.
ぜひフルセットね、購入していただけたら嬉しいなと、はい、思ってます。
I'd be happy if you purchased the full set.
はい、そして、二つ目のお知らせ、こちら。
And now for the second announcement, here it is.
なんと、獅白ぼたんの新曲「Stray & Stay」、このあと24時、えー、9月20日日曜日の0時からデジタルリリースされます！
Shishiro Botan's new song, 'Stray & Stay,' will be digitally released tonight at midnight—specifically, 0:00 AM on Sunday, September 20th!
今回は、えーっと、「SHIMIRACUL」作ってくれた、Cino先生が作ってくれたんですよ、また。ありがとうございます。
This time, Cino-sensei, who wrote 'SHIMIRACUL,' wrote this song for me again. Thank you so much.
これは、なんかね、多分、スルメ曲だと思うんですよ。
This one is, well, probably a 'dried squid song' (a song that gets better the more you listen to it).
なんかずっと味がある。
It's like it has a long-lasting flavor.
味、味がする。ずっとリピートしてもらえると、
Yeah, you get a flavor. If you keep looping it,
なんかどんどん、どんどん、なんか、
it will gradually...
噛めば噛むほど。
The more you chew on it.
ドパドパしてくんじゃないかなと。
...release more and more dopamine, I think.
ドパドパしてくんじゃない？
Dopamine?
ドパドパ？ドパドパじゃないだろ。
"Dopa-dopa"? That's not a word.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Anyway, please check it out.
はい。
Yes!
この配信が終わった後、MV公開されますので、
The MV will be released right after this stream,
ぜひお楽しみに、ということで。
so please look forward to it.
新曲、ちなみにこの後披露しますので、絶対に聞いてください。
By the way, I'll perform the new song next, so make sure to listen.
はい、聞いてください！
Yes, please listen!
そして、3つ目のお知らせ、まだまだあります！
And now, for the third announcement. We're not done yet!
こちら！ドン！
Here it is! Boom!
ということで、私、獅白ぼたんのファーストアルバムが発売決定しました！
My first album, "BOTAN.EXE," is officially releasing!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
素晴らしい！
Amazing!
記念すべき、はい、ファーストアルバムということで、たっぷり10曲入ってます！
For this memorable first album, it's packed with 10 tracks!
おおー！
Oh!
今年リリースした「Simulacre」から「Tokehanate」の4曲に加えて、
In addition to the four songs released this year from "Simulacre" to "Tokehanate,"
この生誕ライブに合わせて、椎乃味醂さんに書き下ろしてもらった新曲「Stray & Stay」ももちろん収録されてます。
it also features "Stray & Stay," a new song written for this birthday live by Shiinomirin!
おおー！
Wow!
さらに、さらに、まだちょっとネタバレになっちゃうから、伏せたいんですけど、
And on top of that—I want to keep it under wraps because of spoilers, but...
素敵なクリエイターの皆様に書き下ろしていただいた新曲、５曲入ってます！
it features five brand-new songs written by wonderful creators!
5曲も！？
Five songs?!
5曲？言えない、何曲？何、何曲だっけ？
Wait, how many? Five? I can't do the math.
何曲？もうわかんない。足し算できない。
How many? I don't know anymore. I can't add!
えー、獅白ぼたんのね、音楽を存分に感じてもらえる１枚になってるかなと思いますので、
I think this album lets you fully experience Shishiro Botan's music,
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
so I hope you'll check it out.
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please support it!
そして、アルバムゲットしてくれた皆さんに感謝の気持ちを込めて、全員に直筆サイン入りのグッズも用意しております。
And to show my gratitude, everyone who gets the album will receive hand-signed merchandise!
全員！？
Everyone?!
その他、たくさん、ここでしか手に入らない、えーと、こだわりグッズ詰め込んでますので、
We've also packed in lots of exclusive, special items that you can only get here,
ぜひ詳細は公式ページをチェックしていただけたら嬉しいです。
so please check the official page for details!
はーい！
Okay!
本当におめでとうございます。
Huge congratulations to you!
このアルバムはですね、ホロライブ公式オンラインショップで、この後予約開始となります。
Pre-orders for this album will open on the Hololive Official Online Shop right after this stream.
はい、頑張って作ったファーストアルバムなので、たくさんの人に手に取ってもらえると嬉しいです。
I worked really hard on this first album, so I hope many people will get to enjoy it.
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Thank you so much!
そしてですね、まだあるんですよ、実は。
And actually, there's still more.
え、まだあるの！？お腹いっぱいだよ！
What, more?! I'm already so full of news!
ラストのこのお知らせ、結構重大発表なので、こちらご覧ください！ドン！
This last announcement is a major one. Take a look! Boom!
ええー！？
What?!
緊急告知！獅白ぼたん、特殊なオフイベ、
Urgent Announcement! Shishiro Botan's unique offline event...
特殊なオフイベ！？開催決定！
A unique offline event?! ...is officially happening!
ということで、2027年2月末〜3月中旬あけといてね！
So keep late February to mid-March 2027 open!
え、長く？長く？
Wait, that long?
かっこ、１日じゃないよ！
Note: It's not just for one day!
１日じゃないの！？
It's not just one day?!
ということで、皆さん、ぜひ楽しみにしといてもらえたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
So everyone, I hope you'll look forward to it.
まだ詳細はね、ごめん、ちょっと言えないんだけど、
I'm sorry I can't share the details just yet, but...
え、気になる！気になる！
Wow, I'm so curious!
いやね、ねぽらぼ、ねぽらぼの皆さんにもちょっとね、来てほしいなと思いつつ、
I'm actually hoping NePoLaBo can come along as well...
ええ！？本当にいいの？
Really?! Are we allowed to?
よ、なんか、まだ内緒だけどね。
Well, it's still a secret for now.
なんでー！？教えてよー。
Why?! Tell us!
いやいや、まあ、遊びに来てほしいかなって感じ。
No, no. Let's just say I want you all to come and play.
遊びに？
Come and play?
おお、すごーい！楽しみ！
Wow, awesome! Can't wait!
遊びに行くなら全力でふざけちゃうよ。ふざけにいきます。
If we're going there to play, we're going to goof off with all our might.
ふざけてほしい。期待してる。
I expect nothing less.
まあ、2月末から3月中旬予定になっておりますので、
Anyway, it's scheduled from late February to mid-March,
ぜひちょっと、あの、情報解禁いろいろね、またしていくので、チェックよろしくお願いします。
and more details will be revealed in the future, so keep an eye out!
以上、獅白ぼたん誕生日記念2026のグッズ情報、アルバムリリース情報、新曲情報、そして重大発表でした！
And that's all for Shishiro Botan's Birthday 2026 merch, album release, new song, and major announcement!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much!
じゃあみんな、はい、スタンバイ、スタンバイ。
Alright everyone, standby!
ここからはですね、いよいよ、あの、ライブも終盤戦ということで、
From here on, we're finally reaching the final stretch of the live stream.
ねぽらぼのみんなも、この後一緒に歌わせていただきますので、
The rest of NePoLaBo will be singing together with me in a bit,
リスナーの皆さん、ぜひ楽しみに待っててください。
so please look forward to it, everyone!
あと、アンコールライブも今日ありますので、ぜひそちらも来ていただけたら嬉しいです。
Also, we have an encore live today as well, so please join us there too!
アンコールあるで！楽しみや！
There's an encore! I can't wait!
じゃあ、私ちょっと次の曲、に衣装に着替えるんで、じゃあみんな、ちょっと繋いどいてもらっていい？
I'm going to change outfits for the next song, so could you guys keep the stage warm?
はーい！繋いどく、繋いどく。
Sure! We'll keep things going.
ししろの特殊なオフイベ予想しよう。
Let's try guessing what Botan's unique offline event is.
あ、いいね、いいね。でもそれ当たっちゃったらどうするの？
Oh, good idea! But what if we actually get it right?
当たっちゃわない程度に、大きく行こう、大きく。
Let's think big so we don't accidentally guess it correctly.
じゃあ、ししろランド開催、みたいな。
How about opening "Shiro Land"?
いいね！動物園、動物園。
Nice! Like a zoo!
そう、それとかどう？特殊なオフイベって、しかも特殊って言ってるからな。
Yeah, how about that? Since she specifically called it "unique."
お、戻ってきた。
Oh, she's back.
これ以上、これ以上言うとバレる可能性があるからな。
If you guys say any more, you might actually leak it.
やばいやばい！やめろやめろ！危ない！
Oh no! Stop, stop! That was close!
当たるかもしれないからね。
Because you might actually hit the nail on the head.
じゃあ当てられそうだったからちょっと。着替えてきました。
You were getting too close, so I rushed back. I've changed!
ということで、じゃあ、あの、ねぽらぼのみんなも、ちょっと準備して。
Alright, the rest of NePoLaBo, go get ready too.
準備してきます！
We'll go get ready!
ありがとう。また後でね！バイバーイ！
Thank you! See you later! Bye-bye!
ということで、ねぽらぼともこの後歌うんですが、まずはちょっと次の曲、私の新曲を聞いていただきたいなと思います。
So, I'll be singing with NePoLaBo later, but first, I'd like you to hear my new song.
ぜひ聞いてください。
Please enjoy it.
それでは、「Stray & Stay」。
Up next, "Stray & Stay."
Stray & Stay / 作詞・作曲・編曲：椎乃味醂
[Song: Stray & Stay / Lyrics, Composition, & Arrangement: Shiinomirin]
Losing the faint light, mmm...
形のない、層に沈む 感覚の様
Shape-less, like a sensation sinking into layers.
不安定な位相が
An unstable phase...
走る思考から落ちた記憶を捜す
...searching for memories fallen from running thoughts.
昨日と同じ軌道を描く日常に
In a daily life that traces the same orbit as yesterday,
散らばった 霞がかったシニョール
scattered, hazy signals.
Stay, stay, stay in my own place.
Stray, without a trace.
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が
Before the jumbled words
消えてしまう前に
disappear completely...
掴みたいと
I want to grasp it,
願った。
I wished.
ただ繰り返した
I just repeated it,
また繰り返して
Repeating it again,
repeating it again,
また繰り返して
まだ、離さないでいて。
Please don't let go of me yet.
Waking from a shallow sleep, mmm...
形のない、夜に滲む 知覚の様
Shape-less, like a perception blending into the night.
未完成な鼓動
An incomplete heartbeat,
またも煌々と輝く、仮構を辿る
shining brightly once again, tracing a fiction.
同じ過去を辿る焦燥に
In the impatience of tracing the same past,
掬いきれぬ透明なもの
something transparent that cannot be scooped up.
Sway, sway, sway out of place.
Stray, fading away.
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が
Before the jumbled words
色褪せる前に
fade away...
書き留めたいと
I want to write it down,
思った。
I thought.
ただ繰り返した
I just repeated it,
また繰り返して
Repeating it again,
repeating it again,
また繰り返して
まだ、忘れないでいて。
Please don't forget me yet.
共に限界まで Burning! X-BRAVER'S
Together to the limit, Burning! X-BRAVER'S
Are you ready? Fight!
Lala... Rurila...
何度地べたに這いずり 土を噛んだって
No matter how many times we crawl and bite the dust,
防ぎ合い 背を任す 戦場に咲く 友がいる
defending each other, there are friends blooming on the battlefield.
ガチンコで本気 危険在時も なぜか？ 立ち向かえ
Genuinely serious, even in dangerous times, why? Stand up and face it!
スフォルツァンドの臨界値まで フォルテーロ 銀河に羽搏けよ
To the critical limit of sforzando, Fortello, flap your wings into the galaxy!
Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn!
ブルったって 突き出せる
Even if we tremble, we can push forward!
Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn! Burn!
たとえ壊れても 振り絞れ
Even if we break, squeeze out every last drop!
人が作る想いの 答えを信じよう
Let's believe in the answer of the feelings people create.
ハートを震わせて 愛を殴れ
Make your heart tremble, strike with love!
100度負けても101度目に 勝てるこの源とは？
Even if we lose 100 times, what is the source that lets us win on the 101st?
みんなが（歴史が）紡いだ この歌と響きが
This song and resonance spun by everyone (by history)...
交わる勇気 託し合って
entrusting each other with crossing courage,
Never Give up! さあ夜明けへと
Never give up! Now, towards the dawn!
怖さ 弱さ 涙は
Fear, weakness, and tears...
ちぎっては消えない 勝利を掴め！
...cannot be torn away and disappear. Grasp victory!
握れば握るほど また開く意味を知り
The more we grasp, the more we learn the meaning of opening again.
相手の悲痛が伝わり 無刀の極みへ焦がれる
Feeling the opponent's grief, yearning for the height of weaponlessness.
因縁の連鎖にこそ 撃鉄を起こせ
Within the chain of fate, cock the hammer of the gun...
この世界 レクイエムじゃなく 奏で合ったら？
What if we play this world, not as a requiem?
オレの知らない 温もりが
A warmth that I never knew...
「誰かの想い出」の中 生きているのだとしたら？
If we are living within "someone's memory"...
完全否定以外にも 足掻く道があるんだと
...that there is a path to struggle, other than complete denial.
だから絶対 この手と
So, definitely, with this hand and...
不器用な この手は
...this clumsy hand...
差し伸べる祈りを 忘れはしない
...we will never forget the prayer we reach out with.
だから 抗え！ 痛みを抱き
So, resist! Embracing the pain,
わかり合える そう ぶち込め！
we can understand each other. Yes, let it rip!
みんなが作った この歌の願いだ！
This is the wish of the song everyone made!
重なる勇気 許す勇気
Overlapping courage, forgiving courage,
Never give up! さあ 全生命（すべて）
never give up! Come on, all of life!
善も悪も ごった煮の
Love this world...
世界を愛せ！
...where good and evil are all mixed together!
Love this world!
大好きな歌の中から
From within my favorite song,
声にしてもいいのかな？
is it alright to put it into words?
思い出が強さになった
My memories became my strength.
君ならば歌えるはず
If it's you, you should be able to sing it.
今日という過去が生まれて
The past called 'today' is born,
未来にはどういたいか？
how do you want to be in the future?
描くんだ 心から
Paint it from the bottom of your heart.
オレは「ありがとう」を
I want to take this "thank you"...
歌ってあげたいんだ
...and sing it for you!
100度負けても 101度目に
Even if we lose a hundred times, on the hundred and first...
勝てると微笑う この源（ちから）とは？
...we'll smile and win. What is this power?
みんなで繋いだ この歌の響きだ！
It's the echo of this song that everyone connected!
交わる勇気 託し合って
Intersecting courage, entrusting each other,
Never give up! さあ 夜明けへの
never give up! Come on, towards the dawn!
始まりを 吠え歌え
Howl and sing of the beginning!
X-BRAVERS
勝利を掴め！
seize the victory!